Guide to the Stanford University Film Collection SC1032
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University film collection
circa 1920s-1998
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University
SC1032
293 item(s)
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Letter designation for films:
Size: A less than 6" in diameter B between 6 and 9" C 9" D 10" E 12" F 14" and larger
Length: AA- up to 100' A - up to 400' - 11 minutes B - up to 800' - 22 minutes C - up to 1200' - 33 minutes D - up to 1600" - 44 minutes F - over 1600'
Stanford University -- Students.; Stanford University -- History.; College students -- California -- Stanford.; Stanford University -- Athletics; Football.; motion pictures (visual works); Dornbusch, Sanford M.; Hoover, Herbert; King, Martin Luther, Jr.; Stanford University
- Films
  - Stanford Medical Center, circa 1959; A 1.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 5 min
    Scope and Contents note
    Creator: Larry Williams Production
    General note
    includes shots in SF and on campus
    Alway, Robert
  - Stanford Medical Center (outtakes), 1959; A 1.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 3 min
    Creator: Larry Williams
  - Stanford Hospital, circa 1959; A 2.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 2 min
    Creator: [personal movie]
    Stanford campus MC
  - Hoover Library, circa 1955-59; B 3.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 4 min
    Creator: Doug Allen, director
    Mostly interior shots
  - Hoover Library (duplicate), 1955; B 3.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 4 min
  - Hoover Library (negative), 1955; B 3.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Elmer Fagan, lecture, 1962; B 4.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Creator: Matt Lehman
    Lecture on economics; all 3 reels stored in 1 can.
    Economics
  - Elmer Fagan, lecture (mag track), 1962; B 4.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Elmer Fagan, lecture (b/w workprint), 1962; B 4.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Your Stanford Camp (negative: A roll), B 5.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Your Stanford Camp (negative: A roll), B 5.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - PACE Announcement Luncheon, 1961 Apr; B 6.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 9:44 min
    See V316.1 for DVD copy
    Sterling, J. E. Wallace (John Ewart Wallace)
  - PACE Announcement Luncheon (mag track), 1961 Apr; B 6.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    MAGNETIC SOUND TRACK
  - Stanford Hospital Construction, 1959-1960; B 7.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 5:14 min
  - ROTC, B 8.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 8:00 min
  - Let's Look at Stanford, circa 1955-59; B 9.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 3:00 min
  - Let's Look at Stanford (outtakes & print), circa 1955-59; B 9.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 7:00 min
    Professor Benjamin
  - Let's Look at Stanford (Stanford scene outs I), circa 1955-59; D 9.3; 12 film reel(s) (16mm); 33:00 min
  - Let's Look at Stanford (Stanford scene outs II), circa 1955-59; D 9.4; 22 film reel(s) (16mm); 25:00 min
  - Let's Look at Stanford (Stanford scenes I), circa 1955-59; B 9.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 8 min
  - Political Rally White Plaza, 1960's; B 10.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 3 min
    Creator: home movie/ student production
  - Political Rally White Plaza (negative), 1960's; B 10.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 3 min
  - Student film: Miller / Arnold / Suppes (optical track), B 11.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 6:30 min
    Creator: student film: Miller, Arnold, Suppes
  - Student film: Miller / Arnold / Suppes, B 11.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 8 min
  - Student film: Miller / Arnold / Suppes (Mag track), B 11.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 8 min
  - What Caused This Accident, B 12.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 6 min
  - Stanford / Palo Alto Community, circa 1950's; B 13.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 6:50 min
    Creator: Miller, Jordan, Herrick
  - Stanford / Palo Alto Community / Shopping Center, 1958; B 13.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 18 min
  - Stanford / Palo Alto Community / Shopping Center, 1958; B 13.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 6 min
  - Palo Alto Community, circa 1955-59; C 13.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
    Creator: Miller, Jordon, Herrick
  - Stanford / Palo Alto Community, circa 1955-59; B 13.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 6 min
  - Stanford Shopping Center, circa 1955-59; D 13.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 17 min
  - Stanford Antartica, B 14.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 10min
  - Stauffer Chemistry Building dedication, circa 1960's; B 15.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    President Sterling
  - Stanford Football (reel 1), 1965; B 16.1; 12 film reel(s) (16mm); 10min
    includes Big Game footage
    Football.
  - Stanford Football (reel 2), 1965; B 16.2; 22 film reel(s) (16mm); 8:31 min
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game (reel 1), 1964; B 17.1; 13 film reel(s) (16mm); 12 min
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game (reel 2), 1964; B 17.2; 23 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game (reel 3), 1964; B 17.3; 33 film reel(s) (16mm); 11 min
  - SCIRE: Its Your Thing, 1977; B 18.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 2:30 min
  - SCIRE: Its Your Thing, 1977; B 18.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 2:30
    Creator: Meg Donavan
  - School of Physical Sciences (reel 1), 1944; B 19.1; 14 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
    Creator: Mervyn V. Miller
  - School of Physical Sciences (reel 2), 1944; B 19.2; 24 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
  - School of Physical Sciences (reel 3), 1944; B 19.3; 34 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
    Chemistry.
  - School of Physical Sciences (reel 4), 1944; B 19.4; 44 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
    Geology.
  - School of Physical Sciences. Doctoral Thesis of Mervyn V. Miller. Print #2, 1944; E 19.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    This copy transferred from Cubberley; did not view but presumably is the complete film. Note on can indicated sound does not start until all titles are done.
  - Light as a Feather [construction of the Dish telescope], circa 1959; B 20.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 6 min
  - Hungarian Dances, 1972; B 21.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 5 min
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game, 3rd quarter, 1952; B 22.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game (reel 1), 1948; B 23.1; 13 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game (reel 2), 1948; B 23.2; 23 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game (reel 3), 1948; B 23.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 4 min
  - They Come to Learn, 1960's; E 24.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 26 min
  - They Come to Learn (duplicate), 1930's; E 24.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 26 min
    Creator: Mattt Lehman
  - They Come to Learn (Stanford in Europe outs), 1960's; B 24.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
  - They Come to Learn (Stanford in Europe outs), 1960's; D 24.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 30 min
    Creator: Matt Lehman?
  - They Come to Learn (mag track), 1960s; D 24.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - They Come to Learn (mag track), 1960s; D 24.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - They Come to Learn (mag track for B24.3), 1960s; D 24.7; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - They Come to Learn (Duplicate), E 24.8; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - They Come to Learn (mag track), E 24.9; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Computer Generated Images on the Gunn Effect, B 25.1; 16 film reel(s) (16mm); 8 min
    Creator: Imagine Shockly
    Shockly Papers
  - Shape of the Future, circa 1955; C 26.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 16 min
    Creator: The Office of University Relations
  - Shape of the Future (duplicate), circa 1955; C 26.2; 2 film reel(s) (16mm); 15-17 min
  - Shape of the Future (duplicate), circa 1955; C 26.3; 2 film reel(s) (16mm); 15-17 min
  - Speeches, misc. at Memorial Auditorium, 1962 Feb; C 27.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 11 min
  - CPR teaching film, circa 1958; C 28.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 12 min
  - Tresidder Union Dedication, 1962; C 29.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 11min
  - Tresidder Union Dedication (mag track), 1962; C 29.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 11 min
  - Campaign for Stanford, 1975; C 30.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 10 min
    Creator: Ken Zunder; produced by Dept. of Comm., grant from Stanford Associates
    See V317.1 for DVD copy
  - Stanford in Autumn, 1948; D 31.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 14 min.
    Creator: E. P. Hunt. Stanford Alumni Assoc. and Stanford Associates
  - Stanford in Autumn (duplicate), 1948; D 31.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford in Autumn (outtakes), 1948; C 31.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 8 min
  - Stanford in Autumn (duplicate), 1948; D 31.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Football [assorted clips], 1979-1982; C 32.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 17 min
    Creator: SU Sports Information Office
    Football.; Elway, John
  - Challenging Era, circa 1962; E 33.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 28 min
    Creator: Sound & Scene Inc. (?)
    see V315 for DVD copies
    Fund raising.
  - Challenging Era (outtakes), circa 1962; D 33.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 14 min
  - Challenging Era (duplicate), circa 1962; E 33.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Challenging Era (duplicate), circa 1962; E 33.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Smoke Signal (negative: A roll), circa 1960; D 34.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 15 min.
    Tokyo Overseas Study Center
  - Stanford Smoke Signal (negative: B roll), circa 1960; D 34.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 15 min.
  - Stanford Smoke Signal (optical sound track), 1960; D 34.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 15 min.
  - Stanford Smoke Signal (Dedication Tokyo Center), circa 1960; D 34.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 18 min.
    Creator: Comm. Department
    Tokyo Overseas Study Center; Sterling
  - Stanford Smoke Signal (mag sound track), 1960; D 34.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Smoke Signal (reference print), 1959; D 34.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color
    Creator: News and Publications Service
    No notes on original form to indicate if this is also about Tokyo Overseas Study Center dedication, but it's likely.
  - Stanford in Germany, circa 1950; D 35.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 21 min
    Stanford in Germany
  - Stanford in Germany (duplicate), circa 1950; D 35.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 21 min.
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game, 1st half (reel 1), 1937; D 37.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 17 min.
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game, 2nd half (reel 2), 1937; D 37.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 17 min
  - Keys to the Library, 1950s; D 38.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 13 min
    Creator: Kugler Barker Production
    possibly not unique to Stanford
  - Sixty Summers: Children's Hospital at Stanford [includes old footage from 1924 - 40s], 1976; D 39.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 20 min
    Creator: Elliot, Elspeth
    graduate student thesis (AM 1978)
  - President Sterling Inauguration, 1949 Apr 1; D 40.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 21 min.
    Creator: Moulin Studios
    Stanford University -- Presidents.; Sterling, J. E. Wallace (John Ewart Wallace)
  - Stanford Football, assorted clips, 1977-1982; D 41.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 23 min.
    Creator: Athletics Dept.
    Original notes include details on individuals
  - Success Story: Hoover Institution, 1950s; E 42.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 29 min
    Creator: Caryl Coleman
  - Arithmetic Workshop (reel 1), E 43.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 30 min.
    Creator: Univ. of Oklahoma
    Not a Stanford related film
    Lewis, Eunice
  - Arithmetic Workshop (reel 2), E 43.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Arithmetic Workshop (reel 3), E 43.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Arithmetic Workshop (reel 4), E 43.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Arithmetic Workshop (reel 5), E 43.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Arithmetic Workshop (reel 6), E 43.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford in Italy, 1961; D 44.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 28 min
    Creator: David Geeting [student film - AM 1964 in communications]
    Stanford in Italy
  - Hungarian Dance, Stanford International Folk Dances [no date noted], E 45.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 15 min
  - Stanford Orchesis Modern Dance, 1964; E 46.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 30 min
    silent - no music
  - Day Before Tomorrow, 1969; E 47.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 28 min.
    Creator: Newsweek, Osborn Elliot editor
  - Measure of Man: The Sense of Humor [John W. Dodds], E 48.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 28 min
    Creator: KQED
    Dodds, John W. (John Wendell)
  - Measure of Man: the Dignity of Man [John W. Dodds], E 48.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    no inventory worksheet on this one
  - Measure of Man: The Sense of Tragedy [John W. Dodds], E 48.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Measure of Man: the Tranquilizer [John W. Dodds], E 48.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Measure of Man: Are Americans Civilized [John W. Dodds], E 48.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Measure of Man: Loyalties [John W. Dodds], E 48.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - USA - USSR, International Track Classic, 1962; E 49.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 30 min.
    Creator: Sound & Scene Inc.
    Held at Stanford Stadium
  - Stanford vs. USC, Football, 1968; E 50.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 30 min.
  - Success Story: Stanford Electronics and Research Lab, 1954; D 51.1; 2 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 28 min
    9 part series: 51.1 through 51.9. Inventory sheet only on 51.1
    Electronics
  - Success Story: U. S. Steel, D 51.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Success Story: Kaiser Aluminum, D 51.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Success Story: Consolidated Western Steel, D 51.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Success Story: Bethelehem Steel, D 51.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Success Story: Enterprise Engine, D 51.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Success Story: Norton Co., D 51.7; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Success Story: Lenkurt Electric Co., D 51.8; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Success Story: Chrysler Corp, D 51.9; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: International Communism (#10), E 52.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Inventory sheet only for 52.1
  - Red Myth: What is Communism (#1), E 52.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 30 min.
    Creator: NET, produced by Matt Lehman for KQED
  - Red Myth: Communism in the U.S. (#11), E 52.11; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: Kruschev, I (#12), E 52.12; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: Kruschev, II (#13), E 52.13; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: Birth of Bolshevism (#2), E 52.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: Theory and Tactics (#3), E 52.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: the War (#4), E 52.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: Overthrow of Social Democracy (#5), E 52.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: Lenin Takes OVer (#6), E 52.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: The Great Design (#7), E 52.7; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: The Stalin Era, I (#8), E 52.8; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Red Myth: The Stalin Era, II (#9), E 52.9; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Winds of Freedom, 1958; E 53.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 27 min
    Creator: Matt Lehman / S.U.
  - Winds of Freedom (duplicate), 1958; E 53.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 27 min
  - Winds of Freedom (duplicate), 1958; E 53.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 27 min
  - Winds of Freedom (duplicate), 1958; E 53.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 27 min
  - Senator Fulbright [giving a speech], circa 1960; E 54.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color; 30 min
    This film was shown at PACE conference held at Cubberley
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game, 1963; E 55.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Orchesis Modern Dance, 1962; E 56.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - SCIRE, 1972; E 57.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford in Wartime, circa 1944; E 58.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    several video formats in Video collection
  - American Memoirs: Culture of the Millions, 1958; E 59.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: The Automotive American, 1958; E 59.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: The Radio, 1958; E 59.11; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: How Historical is History, 1958; E 59.12; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: Everybody's Dreamhouse, 1958; E 59.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: Adland Revisited, 1958; E 59.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: Best Sellers Since 1900, 1958; E 59.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: 60 Years of Satire, 1958; E 59.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: The Businessman is Here, 1958; E 59.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: 60 Years of Magazines, 1958; E 59.7; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: The Hero in the 20th Century, 1958; E 59.8; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - American Memoirs: The Movies, 1958; E 59.9; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Oasis: Online Administrative Information, E 60.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Football, 1982; E 61.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Experience No. 1, 1980s; E 62.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Rose Bowl, 1980; E 63.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Rose Bowl, 1981; E 64.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Challenge [football], 1981; E 65.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    DO NOT PROJECT - IN BAD SHAPE
  - Stanford vs. Ohio State, Football, 1956; F 66.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W; 36 min
    date determined from research based on viewing notes: noted that in previous year Stanford won 6-0 and that happened in 1955.
    Football.; Brodie, John.
  - Edge of Greatness, circa 1962; F 67.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color
    Creator: Stanford University, Ernest Kleinberg, producer
    See V318.1 for DVD copy
  - Edge of Greatness (duplicate), circa 1962; F 67.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color
  - Edge of Greatness (duplicate), circa 1962; F 67.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color
  - Edge of Greatness (duplicate), circa 1962; F 67.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color
  - University in Society: Do the Ties Bind, 1969; F 68.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Converations with Mr. Hoover (reel 1), circa 1960; F 69.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Converations with Mr. Hoover (reel 2), circa 1960; F 69.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Womens Physical Education, circa 1960; D 70.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Womens Physical Education (rushes), A 70.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Womens Physical Education (outs), A 70.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Ski Team Meets, 1946-1947; B 71.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford on Skis, 1940s; B 72.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Dry Skiing at Stanford University, 1938; B 73.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Tennis Film, B 74.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher, 1987; C 75.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Creator: John Cremer
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (mos roll 3), 1987; D 75.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (mos roll 4), 1987; D 75.11; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher, 1987 1987; D 75.12; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (sync roll 1), 1987; D 75.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher, 1987 1987; C 75.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Possibly an edited version; note on can indicates it was going to SITN.
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (sync roll 2), 1987; D 75.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (sync roll 3), 1987; D 75.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (sync roll 4), 1987; D 75.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (sync roll 5), 1987; D 75.5; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (sync roll 6), 1987; D 75.6; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (sync roll 7), 1987; D 75.7; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (mos roll 1), 1987; D 75.8; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (mos roll 2), 1987; D 75.9; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - True Source of Knowledge, 1965; E 76.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford campus, E 77.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Fathers and Sons (reel 1), 1969; E 78.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Creator: Don Lenzer. copyright 1969 Public Broadcast Library
    Beta Video transfer done 1999
  - Fathers and Sons (reel 2), 1969; F 78.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Pitzer, Kenneth S.
  - Beyond Conception, 1968; F 79.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Vasectomy Technique, 1971; D 80.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Case for Population Control, 1970; E 81.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Ehrlich, Paul R.
  - Herbert Hoover, Master of Emergencies, D 82.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Anthony & Cleopatra; Ceasar & Cleopatra, 1936; A 83.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Twelfth Night, 1937; A 84.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    first production in Memorial Auditorium
  - Court and country Dances of the 16th Century, 1937; A 85.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    First performance in Frost Amphitheatre
  - Tempest, 1939; A 86.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Dances of Poland, B 87.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford vs. Washington, football, 1936; B 88.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Speech, Robert Glaser, Acting President of LSJU, 1968; B 89.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Fiftieth Anniversary Celebration, 1941; C 90.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Track & Field, D 91.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Football, 1949; D 92.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Herbert Hoover at Stanford on his 75th Birthday, 1949 Aug 10; D 93.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford: The World Within, D 94.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Video (beta) Film-to-tape transfer made 3/23/99 (V244)
  - Stanford vs. Cal: Big Game, 1965; E 95.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Meet the Professor: Sanford Dornbush, 1962; E 96.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Austrian Campus Dedication (negative), E 97.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Rhythmic Ball Exercises (Women's Physical Education), C 98.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Horizon (Feigenbaum, SC0340), F 100; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Up Toward Mountains Higher (unedited footage) [film and audio tapes], 1987; 101; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips of Vaugh Williams, circa 1982; A 102; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips of Steve Dils, 1977; A 103; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips of John Elway, 1982; A 104.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football: Elway v. Oklahoma, A 104.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football: John Elway, 1982; A 104.3; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football: John Elway, circa 1982; A 104.4; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips of Darrin Nelson, no. 1, 1977; A 105.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips of Darrin Nelson, no. 2, 1977; A 105.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips of Darrin Nelson, no. 1, 1978; A 106.1; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips of Darrin Nelson, no. 2, 1978; A 106.2; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips: Stanford v. Tulane, 1980; A 107; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips: Stanford v. Oklahoma, circa 1980; A 108; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Football clips unidentified, A 109; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Women on Orgasm, circa 1970; C 111; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Stanford Today - Sports Highlights, May 1979; D 112; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Rose Bowl, 4th quarter highlights, 1971, 1972; B 113; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Women's Athletic Events, 1936-1940; 114; 27 film reel(s) (16mm)
  - Protein Synthesis (Paul Berg), 1971; D 115; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    Rewound on new core
  - Shakey: Experiments in Robot Planning and Learning, E 116; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    see V326 for DVD transfer of this film (done during the AAAI project Fall 2008). See also SC 944, 2009-119, box 8.
    Artificial intelligence.
  - Career Decision Making, 1974; E 117; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); Color
    Creator: Counseling Films, Inc.
    "Written by John D. Krumboltz and Don L. Sorenson part of Krumboltz's papers SC 219"
    Krumboltz, John
  - Behavioral Therapy of Client-Centered Therapy. C.H. Patterson and John D. Krumboltz, circa 1969; F 118; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); B/W
    "on leader: "dialogue part I and II" part of Krumboltz's papers SC 219"
    Psychology.
  - An Introduction to Behavioral Counseling, unknown; E 119; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    part of Krumboltz's papers SC 219
    Psychology.; Krumboltz, John D.
  - A Behavioral Counseling Seminar, unknown; D 120; 1 film reel(s) (16mm)
    "a rental copy; part of Krumboltz's papers SC 219"
  - Careers in Banking. B version., unknown; E 121; 1 film reel(s) (16mm); 29.5 min
    Creator: Butler Productions, Inc.